# Curriculum Vitae

## Personal Information

Name Christoph Hartleb Date of Birth Jun 13th, 1995

Address L'Hospitalet de Llobregat, 08908, Barcelona

Mobile 616 745 848

Email quim.motger@gmail.com



## Presentation

I'm a Computer Science Engineer with specialization in Software Engineer graduated from Facultat d'Informàtica de Barcelona (UPC). I have 3 years of experience as Java back-end software engineer, both in design/planification and implementation tasks in different international projects at the university, working alongside companies and other universities. I also have some basic experience in front-end development tools. As a freelance developer, I'm currently working in two mobile app projects, and I have some experience in web development as well.

## Education

2013–2017 Bachelor Degree in Informatics Engineering, specialization in Software Engineering, Facultat d'Informàtica de Barcelona, Universitat Politècnica de Catalunya

2011–2013 High School Education, IES Baix Montseny, Sant Celoni

# Experience

2015-Present **Technical research support,** ESSI - Universitat Politècnica de Catalunya, Barcelona. Java software developer in projects from the Research & Innovation European Comission.

- o RISCOSS, Seventh Framework Programme. A platform to assist the detection and management of potential risks of the use of open source software. Tasks: web application front-end implementation using GWT; Java back-end development; basic non-relational database query implementation.
- o SUPERSEDE, Horizon 2020 Programme. A feedback-driven approach platform for improving software's quality of service. Tasks: design and implementation of RESTful services; component architecture and algorithm design, implementation and extension; microservices desing and implementation; JSON formatting and data transmission using Apache Kafka; dynamic model adaptation; web front-end implementation using Spring framework.
- o LLAVOR. A release planning tool based on genetic algorithm optimization solutions. Tasks: analyze and improve use of genetic algorithms; requirement analysis and project planning proposals; software architecture design and refactor tasks for tool improvement

2014-Present Freelance web and mobile app developer Developing simple static websites for small companies and Android mobile applications.

#### Extracurricular Activities

2014 Web programming course, HTML/CSS/Javascript/PHP, CIPSA, Barcelona (200h)

2016 **Training in coaching tools,** *Insitut de Ciències de l'Educació*, Barcelona (10h)

Present **President of Hackers@UPC**, organizers of an international student hackathon hosted in UPC, Barcelona

# Skills & Background Knowledge

#### Technical skills

OS admin skills in Linux and Windows

High skills in C, C++, Java (framework/s: Spring, Swing, Hibernate)

SQL and relational DBMS, and basic NoSQL knowledge

Web development (HTML, CSS, Javascript, PHP) and content management systems

Microservices and RESTful design and implementation experience

Amazon Web Services (web applications and database management)

Apache tools (Tomcat, Kafka, HTTP)

Android native development

Version control systems (Git) and build automation tools (Gradle, Maven)

Agile software development (use of Trello & JIRA), testing and continuous integration

Advanced skills and knowledge in design patterns and software engineering

#### Personal skills

High level in oral and formal written communication skills

Experience and abilities for team working and team leading

Sociable and proactive

# Languages

Spanish Mothertongue

Catalan Mothertongue

English C1 level

Cambridge English FCE (03/16)